[OLRUGGIO]
Mind you don't drop that bundle.
As if I would.
[DAGDA] Sir Witch!
The bridge was just past
that tall pine!
[AGOTT] Please allow me
to come along!
I will be of use to you.
I promise.
You can't.
This isn't something
your training
has prepared you for.
There'll be many people there
who aren't witches.
And since you've not taken
your second test yet,
you aren't allowed
to cast in front of them.
So try to understand.
- I promise you, one day I will--
- [Agott grunts softly]
[AGOTT] When exactly
will that day be?
I practice constantly on my own.
I know how to cast in public.
And I've been preparing
for the test for ages now!
As my teacher,
are you not meant to seek out
chances for me
to gain more experience?
Yes, but even so.
[DAGDA] Please, there's no time!
- [horse neighs]
- Whatever you do,
we need to hurry!
[OLRUGGIO] I'll go on ahead.
Once I get onsite,
I'll set up an exit
for the Windowway.
You prepare the contraptions
and medicine we'll need.
Agott can ride with me.
[Agott exclaims]
[AGOTT]
I'll fetch my cloak and hat!
- We're coming, too!
- [Qifrey exclaims softly]
Ease up a bit, Qifrey.
Some things can only be learned
through hands-on experience.
But I still worry.
Especially about Agott.
She takes little joy
from her achievements.
Fixates on her limitations.
It's no crime
to lack experience.
[Agott pants]
[QIFREY] But she is racing
to grow up.
[Agott grunts]
[QIFREY] So if she missteps,
she'll fall hard.
- [horse neighs]
- [Olruggio and Agott grunt]
The ground looks
none too stable.
[DAGDA] It's here.
It's still here.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[MAN 1] Oh, look! He's back!
And he brought witches!
- [men gasp]
- What a relief.
They came just in time.
Hey! Don't worry,
the witches are here!
- [OLRUGGIO] Agott.
- [indistinct chatter]
[OLRUGGIO] You know
how to use them, I take it?
Help these people
dry off their clothes.
- Then await further orders.
- [Agott grunts]
You just want me to use
a simple contraption.
Nothing else?
But I can do more--
[OLRUGGIO] That's all I need.
Come now.
What's the problem?
You don't think simple tasks
are worth doing?
I can see why Qifrey
was worried then.
Agott...
You're too impatient by half.
[Agott grunts softly]
[OLRUGGIO] If you wish
to flaunt your skills,
there are times
and places for that.
However, if you truly wish to be
useful here and now,
you should take a moment
to reconsider what magic is for.
- [OLRUGGIO] Aye up.
- [AGOTT] Yet again...
[QIFREY] Thank you, Olly.
[AGOTT]... I'm treated
like an ignorant child.
I work harder than anyone,
and I have nothing
to show for it.
There's someone I need
to prove myself to.
I will silence all doubt
that I'm a worthy witch.
[OLRUGGIO] Qifrey!
[Qifrey grunting]
♪
[woman gasps] Amazing.
I can't believe what I'm seeing!
He parted the river
with a sword!
Remain calm and stay away
from the river!
[QIFREY] Olruggio,
how many in the carriage?
Only two!
I'm flying the first out now.
[Qifrey grunting]
The river isn't
making this easy. [grunts]
Thanks for that, water,
I hate you too.
Just hang in there.
On my way back.
Got you. We're done here.
[QIFREY] Understood.
[Qifrey grunts]
[yelling, grunting]
[Qifrey sighs]
[OLRUGGIO] Well done.
Everyone's safe.
We did all right, then.
- [Dagda pants] Custas!
- [CUSTAS] Dagda!
[CUSTAS] I'm sorry.
I... I was trying to save
our equipment, but...
Forget it.
What matters is you're safe.
[DAGDA] You saved his life.
I can't possibly
thank you enough!
No need. I'm just glad
we arrived in time.
My apprentices have brought
medicine for you,
if you're injured,
they're here to...
[BOTH] Uh?
[COCO] Look how the water moves!
[exclaims]
- It's sublime.
- Huh, I must say, it is.
The greatest contraption
ever contrapted!
Master Qifrey,
what is this contraption?
[QIFREY] Oh, this?
We have dubbed it
"the Raincleaver."
The pattern inscribed
into the blade
is made up of Casting Seals.
Though they're quite small,
they're numerous enough
that this blade could carve
a path through the ocean.
[Coco and Tetia gasp]
Can we give it a swing or two?
I think it would be educational!
I disagree.
Magically augmented weapons
must be handled
with utmost care.
It isn't safe,
so no more words about it
'til you're older.
[BOTH] Huh?
[OLRUGGIO] Qifrey!
Just to be thorough,
I think I'll look upriver.
Fair enough.
Then I'll check
the damage downriver.
Tetia, care to join?
[chuckles] Hurrah!
- [OLRUGGIO] Richeh, with me.
- Right.
You two stay.
Keep an eye on things here.
Be safe now.
We will be!
[Agott scoffs]
[COCO] This is so awkward.
I need to hurry
and fix Agott's shoes
so I can give them back.
There. That ought to do it!
Feels better already.
Thanks for the help,
Little Miss Witch.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Little Miss Witch?
Little Miss Witch!
Little Miss Witch! [squeals]
[man grunts]
That's the last of it.
We lost half our cargo.
But it certainly could have
been much worse.
- [DAGDA] Custas!
- [MEN] Huh?
[DAGDA] No! Whatever you're
trying to do, it's not worth it!
Come back!
It's fine,
the water's calm here!
See? There's a nook
in the riverbank.
And some of our stuff
got caught in the eddy.
I'll come back up
as soon as I've grabbed it.
Don't be a fool!
The bank is unstable there.
That's why that nook exists!
Get back here this instant!
Custas!
[Coco gasps]
[all gasp]
♪
No. This can't be... Custas.
[AGOTT] Wait, Mr. Dagda.
You can't!
[MAN] You could cause
another landslide!
- Stop!
- Let go of me!
- That's my son! Custas!
- [COCO] Agott!
[AGOTT] Coco?
She was buri...
- [COCO] Agott!
- [Agott gasps]
[COCO] I'm here! Over here!
Coco, are you all right?
Were you hurt at all?
Can you get out?
I think I'll be okay, for now.
But, uh...
Custas, say something, please!
Custas? [whimpers]
Custas!
No. Please, no. [cries]
What do I...
What?
Oh, of course.
There's a witch right here.
- It's not over!
- [AGOTT] Huh?
[DAGDA] Right?
You can use magic
to help him, can't you?
Please, I'm begging you!
Save my son!
[Agott gasps]
[AGOTT] This is my chance.
Our masters aren't here,
and I can't call them back
without my Sylph Shoes.
Coco's locked down,
and the situation is desperate.
If I save this boy with magic,
I can prove that they were
all wrong about me.
[MAN] Miss Witch?
Please, is there some spell
- that you can use to save him?
- [AGOTT] Uh...
[MAN 1] There must be something
you can do for him, right?
[MAN 2] I wonder what magic
we'll see this time.
[WOMAN] How are you
focused on that?
Custas is in danger!
[Agott breathes shakily]
[OLD MAN] Go on, Agott.
- Prove your worth.
- [Agott gasps]
[WITCH 1] This is the best magic
she can muster.
[WITCH 2] Hmm. It doesn't quite
compare to the other children's.
[FEMALE WITCH 1] Aren't you
taking this seriously?
[FEMALE WITCH 2] Perhaps
she's just a bit mediocre.
[WITCH 2] Are we sure
that this is her daughter?
[FEMALE WITCH 1]
If the child had talent,
we would have seen it by now.
[overlapping chatter]
[ADINA] I had
high hopes for you.
But you've disappointed me,
Agott.
You'll not be my apprentice.
We've no need for dull children
in this family.
[Agott cries]
[AGOTT] Why does my mind
go there now?
At a time like this! Why?
- [COCO] Agott!
- [Agott gasps]
[COCO] What can I do?
There must be something.
Tell me how I can help
from here!
I need a way to save Custas!
So tell me! Tell me what to do!
[Agott gasps]
If you truly wish
to be useful here and now,
you should take a moment
to reconsider
what magic is for.
[Agott grunts softly]
Coco, can you move?
Describe the situation!
What do you see?
[COCO] I see...
I see a...
I'm in a pocket
of the riverbank,
and the current's
a lot slower here.
I don't think
it'll sweep me away, but...
It's so muddy.
I keep slipping!
I don't think I can climb out.
Custas is knocked out.
And the rock he's under
looks too big to move,
even for an adult.
Also...
[gasps]
[AGOTT] Even if her components
were dry,
these people
don't know our secret.
We can't let them see us draw.
What now, Agott?
[AGOTT] I don't know.
[footsteps]
[LULUCI] Easthies...
We've received reports
from a village near Kalhn.
[GALGA] Multiple sightings
of a huge pillar of water.
Somewhere in the Marshwoods
upriver.
Let's go, then.
[AGOTT]
Dire as the situation may seem,
Coco still hasn't given up.
[Coco pants]
[COCO]
If I could just use magic.
- [gasps] Hey, Agott!
- [AGOTT] Hm?
[COCO] Um, I need those things!
[AGOTT] What?
I forgot the name!
The things! Master Olruggio's
inventions?
The two rings!
[gasps] Oh, yes.
The Link Rings!
That sorts half our problem.
[COCO]
Once my Spell Quire's dry,
I can use
the new spell I learned
to levitate the rock.
And then, I'll be able
to save Custas!
[AGOTT] Trouble is...
Coco still can't do it.
The only permissible way
to compose a spell
in front of Outsiders
is to draw
with your pen and paper
hidden in the folds
of your cloak.
That requires muscle memory.
Countless hours of practice.
[Agott gasps]
[inhales deeply]
[Agott grunts softly]
[MAN 1] Is she going
to do something?
[WOMAN] Maybe she needs
more time because she's young...
- [AGOTT] Your attention please.
- [ALL] Uh?
[AGOTT]
I am Qifrey's top apprentice,
I am known
as Agott Arklaum.
And I offer you
this demonstration
of the power residing within me!
[AGOTT]
Countless hours of practice,
so that when the time
came to act,
I wouldn't be frozen by fear.
Even if Coco can't do this...
I can!
[all grunting]
♪
[all gasp]
Beautiful.
[both grunt]
[COCO] I was just
practicing levitation
with the carapace yams.
This can work. I can do it.
Then again...
That seal struggled
to make a yam float.
So I know it can't lift
a boulder this huge.
Not with a seal as small
as a Palm Quire.
- [Custas grunts softly]
- [COCO] Uh?
[COCO] Custas!
Where am I? What happened?
[COCO] You're awake!
What a relief.
- [CUSTAS] Who are you?
- My name is Coco.
I'm a witch.
We both fell
when the bank collapsed.
You remember?
Huh...
So, then,
I guess I'm still alive.
When I saw that bird
of light in the sky,
I thought I was dead for sure.
Oh, the bird?
No, it's nothing like that.
It's just a spell
that my friend cast!
[gasps softly]
A spell my friend cast.
Wait, that's it!
[AGOTT] This won't distract them
for much longer.
Hurry, Coco!
[MAN] Miss.
That spell's certainly nice
to look at,
but what does it do?
[DAGDA] All you did
was put on a light show!
That bird isn't helping
with anything!
Can't you make it carry me
down there?
Or could it pry him loose
somehow
and fly him to safety?
Sorry, I...
[DAGDA] Enough! I'll climb down
and save him myself!
[AGOTT]
If he looks down there now...
[AGOTT] No! Don't do it.
You mustn't!
[Dagda gasps]
[Agott gasps]
- [wind howling]
- [Coco breathes shakily]
[COCO] Pull me in, please!
I... I can't get down!
- [Coco exclaims]
- [Dagda grunts]
[thudding]
- [all exclaim]
- [DAGDA] Custas! Custas!
- [MAN] Dagda, can we help?
- Custas!
[indistinct chatter]
- [MAN 1] How is he?
- [MAN 2] What can we do?
[indistinct chatter]
[COCO] It's still floating!
- It won't stop!
- Coco, how did you...
Uh...
[exclaims softly]
Agott! Agott!
What're you...
[COCO] Thank goodness
it worked! I was so scared!
I'm so... so glad.
We did it, Agott!
Let go of me
and pull yourself together!
Now explain, how did you manage
to deal with that massive rock?
Hold on. What is this?
Sand?
[COCO] Mm-hmm.
I remembered how
with the dragon,
you and Richeh saved us
with a rock-breaking spell.
Right, of course!
Even with smaller Seals,
the Wall Breaker spell could
easily crush that boulder
without hurting the person
beneath it.
[COCO] Exactly.
I couldn't do anything
but watch back then.
But I learned from my friends,
and picked up your spells.
I never could've done this
on my own.
Your shining bird reminded me!
You really saved the day, Agott!
Thank you!
That shining distress beacon
was to call our masters back.
The fact that it was helpful
to you is incidental.
And also, you and I
are not friends!
[wind howling]
[COCO] I really am so glad.
We managed to save him.
Maybe someday, I'll save my mom.
I will.
I know it.
Coco...
[wind blowing]
[both gasp]
[both grunting]
What... What are these things?
Silverwhite Capture Pennants,
I think.
Along with scarlet cloaks,
and winged caps.
They're really here.
The Knights Moralis!
[EASTHIES] Who are you?
You there...
Were you the one
who cast that spell?
[Coco gasps]
[EASTHIES]
Or are you the culprit?
Children or not,
you'll be granted no mercy.
Now, speak.
Which of you is in league
with the Brimmed Caps?
What are you on about?
We don't have anything to do
with the Brimmed Caps!
And none of the magic we used
was forbidden!
We only cast spells
that help people!
- [EASTHIES] Is that so?
- [AGOTT] Huh?
Then what happened there?
[Agott gasps]
[Coco breathes shakily]
[COCO] What...
[COCO] What is this?
What happened?
It didn't stop at the rock.
The whole riverbed...
The whole area turned to sand.
It's even crushing
the river to mist.
[MAN] What is this?
[COCO]
No, my spell couldn't do this.
- [EASTHIES] I see.
- [gasps]
[EASTHIES] So you admit
the spell was yours.
A novice could not wield
such power.
Unless, of course,
she obtained that power
by committing a violation.
[Coco breathes shakily]
[EASTHIES] The laws of the Pact
are absolute.
I hereby relieve you
of your memories.
[Coco gasps]
[♪ closing theme song playing]